

Curriculum vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION Jobaer Ahmed

💎 Kyrkogatan 2E, Igh: 1303; 37132 Karlskrona

***** +46729065452

ahmedjobaer2@gmail.com

http://www.jobaerahmed.com/

Gender Male | Date of birth 6 January 1992

Nationality Bangladeshi



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with 4+ years of experience focusing on the software development with different programming languages. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2021 – Ongoing

CI/CD Developer

Ericsson AB

Ölandsgatan 1, 371 33 Karlskrona

-During my first year, I was working as a consultant from Experis AB

-Automate CI/CD pipelines to enable continuous integration and deployment of software applications.

-Write and optimize scripts (e.g., Python, Bash) to automate build, test, and deployment pro-

-Manage and resolve internal customer issues by providing support through a dedicated helpdesk ticketing system.

Tools & Technology Used:

-groovy, python, json, jenkins, git, maven, kubernetes, docker, spinnaker, microservice

September 2018 – November 2019

Software Engineer

Swisslog Logistics Automation Brodalsvägen 13, 433 38 Partille

-Worked with backend and frontend development.

Tools & Technology Used:

-java, Spring, Jboss, json, weblogic, MSSql, jpql, sql, jenkins, subversion, maven, eclipse

June 2018 – August 2018

Summer Worker

Fricsson

Lindholmspiren 11 417 56 Göteborg

- -Exploring Testing Strategies for Microservice-Based System In Continuous Delivery (5G)
- -Writing python script to analyze JSON APIs and sorting results

PROJECTS

Swisslog Warehouse Management system (Sep 2018 – Nov 2019)

Project Description:(Platform: Windows, Language: Java, sql, jpql, json, maven and xhtml, Application Software: Eclipse)

Curriculum vitae Jobaer Ahmed

We worked on a base product for automating the logistics of a warehouse. We developed different functionalities based on the customer requirements. In Swisslog, we have followed agile approach and used agile practices for completing different projects. There, I worked mostly as a back-end developer, where I needed to write code in JAVA. Besides, I needed to write unit test, system test and integration test.

Aviato (March 2017 – May 2017)

Project Description:(Platform: Windows, Language: Java, Application Software: Android Studio)

An android application; Which gives the user notifications, updates about his/her subscribed flights. Our team consists of 7 members. I was responsible for creating filters for airlines, time-interval filter, collecting data from an external API and displaying that information

EDUCATION

September 2016-May 2021

MSc in Software Engineering and Technology

Chalmers University of Technology, Göteborg, Sweden

SKILLS

Computer skills

- Programming Languages: JAVA (J2SE & J2EE), Groovy, Python, C, ReactJS (basic),
 C++ (Basic)
- Databases: MSSQL, MySql, Oracle 10g
- Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, XHTML, JavaScripts (Basic), JSON, Docker, Microservice
- Java Frameworks and Tools: Spring, Hibernate, JBOSS
- Web Application Servers: Apache Tomcat, Apache Web Server
- Continuous Integration Tool: Travis-CI, Jenkins
- Version Control: Git, Subversion
- Mobile Application Development: Android
- Development Platform: Windows, Linux

Mother tongue Bengali

Other Languages English: Proficient; Swedish: Intermediate

Driving licence E

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Extra Curricular Activities

- Position: Logistic host; CHARM Career fair, 2017
- Role Played: Phadder; CIRC Welcome Reception Spring 2017
- Position: Member (LBG Gothenburg); BEST (October 2016 October 2017)
- Participated Göteborgsvarvet 2018.

REFERENCES

Andreas Westerlund

Line Manager R&D at Ericsson, Karlskrona, Sweden Contact: +46733495266, email: andreas.westerlund@ericsson.com

Martin Davidsson

Software Realization Manager Realization at Swisslog AB, Partille, Sweden Contact: +46706550940, email: martin.davidsson@swisslog.com